National Archives and Records Service Copies of Federal Documentation on Black Workers 5584 A
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
National Archives and Records Service Copies of Federal Documentation on Black Workers
1940-1950
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
National Archives and Records Service
5584 A
6 cubic feet
6 linear ft.
Records (documents).
Facsimile documents gathered by Professor James Gross and Cletus Daniels for their research project on black workers.
7742101
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, October 21, 2013
EAD encoding:
Randall Miles, June 05, 2019
Scope and Contents
Contains employment situation surveys; migration survays; labor market development reports; labor market situation surveys; selective service system reports; field operating reports; labor demand-supply summaries; labor market surveys and other miscellaneous documentation regarding black workers for the period 1941-1948
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: 5584: National Archives and Records Service Copies of Federal Documentation on Black Workers 5584 mf: National Archives and Records Service Copies of Federal Documentation on Black Workers on Microfilm
African Americans -- History -- Sources; United States. National Archives and Records Service.
7742101
- Alabama-California (Box 1)
  - Alabama, 1941-1943 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Scope and Contents
    Employment data for Birmingham, Alabama
  - Alabama, 1942 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Labor Market report for Birmingham, Alabama
  - Alabama, 1942-1944 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Federal Works Agency, Survey of Vacancies in Dwelling of Birmingham, Alabama
  - Alabama, 1943-1945 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    Labor Market Survey of Birmingham, Alabama
  - Alabama, 1943-1945 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    Birmingham Demand-Supply Supplement, March 1945; Labor Market Development Report, September 27 1943
  - Alabama, 1941-1942 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    Required Area Directors Survey for Mobile, Alabama, November 6 1942; Survey of the Employment Situation in the Mobile Area of Alabama, September 29 1942; Survey of the Employment Situation in the Mobile Area of Alabama, December 16 1941; Excerpts from Labor Market Survey of Mobile, Alabama, May 18, 1941; Survey of Vacancies in Dwelling Units of Mobile, Alabama, January 28 1941
  - Alabama, 1941-1943 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    Report on the Employment Situation in Mobile, Alabama, May 1941 - May 1942; Estimate of In-migration into the Mobile, Alabama Labor Market During the Six Months beginning June 1 1943
  - Alabama, 1943-1945 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    Mobile Residual Area Demand-Supply Supplement, July 1944 - January 1945; Labor Market Development Report, December 10 1943
  - Alabama, 1943 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    Labor Market Development Report, June - October 1943; Method Used in determining Item 4, Table C-1, Out-migration, Including Military Service Withdrawals, June 1943
  - Alabama, 1944 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    Mobile Demand-Supply Supplement, March - November 1944
  - Alabama, 1942 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    Labor Market Development Report Mobile Alabama, October 28 1942
  - Arkansas, 1943-1945 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    Labor Market Report Little Rock, Arkansas, March - July 1944, 1943, 1945
  - Arkansas, 1942-1948 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    Employment data for Little Rock, Arkansas
  - Arkansas, 1941-1943 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    Labor Market Development and War Manpower Commission Reports
  - California, 1941 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    Survey of Los Angeles and San Fernando Valley
  - California, 1941-1943 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    Survey on Labor Supply Adequacy in Los Angeles and Employment Situation
  - California, 1942-1943 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - California, 1941-1942 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - California, 1942-1946 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - California, 1942-1946 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    San Diego
  - California, 1942 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    San Francisco
  - California, 1941-1943 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    San Francisco Bay Area
  - California, 1941 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - California, 1941-1942 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    San Diego Area
- Connecticut-Georgia (Box 2)
  - Connecticut, 1940-1942 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    Hartford, Connecticut
  - Connecticut, 1941-1942 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    Hartford Area, Connecticut
  - Connecticut, 1941-1942 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Florida, 1941-1942 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    Jacksonville
  - Jacksonville, Florida, 1942-1944 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Wilmington, Delaware, 1941-1942 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Washington, District of Columbia, 1941-1942 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Washington, District of Columbia, 1944 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Washington, District of Columbia, 1941-1942 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Washington, District of Columbia, 1943-1944 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Washington, District of Columbia, 1943-1945 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Washington, District of Columbia, 1941-1945 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Jacksonville, Florida, 1943-1946 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Jacksonville, Florida, 1943-1944 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Atlanta, Georgia, 1944-1945 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Atlanta, Georgia, 1943 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Savannah, Georgia, 1940-1943 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Atlanta, Georgia, 1941-1944 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Savannah, Georgia, 1946-1947 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Savannah-Brunswick, Georgia, 1944-1947 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Savannah, Georgia, 1943-1946 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Savannah, Georgia, 1942 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Savannah, Georgia, 1943-1944 (Box 2, Folder 23)
- Georgia-Illinois (Box 3)
  - Atlanta, Georgia, 1947-1950 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Atlanta, Georgia, 1942-1944 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Atlanta, Georgia, 1944-1945 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Atlanta, Georgia, 1943-1945 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Atlanta, Georgia, 1943-1946 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Illinois, 1941-1948 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Chicago, Illinois, 1947-1949 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Illinois, 1949 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Chicago, Illinois, 1949 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Chicago, Illinois, 1948 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Chicago, Illinois, 1942-1948 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Chicago, Illinois, 1941 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Chicago, Illinois, 1941-1948 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Chicago, Illinois, 1948 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Chicago, Illinois, 1945-1948 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Chicago and Suburbs, Illinois, 1944 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Calumet and Chicago, Illinois, 1943-1944 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Calumet, Illinois, 1944-1948 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Chicago, Illinois, 1945-1948 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Chicago, Illinois, 1944-1945 (Box 3, Folder 20)
- Illinois-Indiana (Box 4)
  - Chicago, Illinois, 1942-1944 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Chicago-Calumet, Illinois, 1944-1949 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Chicago-Calumet, Illinois, 1943-1949 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Indianapolis, Indiana, 1943-1944 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Chicago, Illinois, 1944-1947 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Chicago-Calumet, Illinois, 1948 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Chicago-Calumet, Illinois, 1947-1949 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Chicago, Illinois, 1943 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Chicago, Illinois, 1943-1944 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Chicago and Suburbs, Illinois, 1943-1944 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Chicago Area, Illinois, 1943-1946 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Chicago, Illinois, 1943-1944 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Chicago, Illinois, 1943 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Chicago, Illinois, 1942-1947 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Gary and Indianapolis, Indiana, 1943-1945 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Indianapolis, Indiana, 1942-1944 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Indianapolis, Indiana, 1942-1943 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Indianapolis, Indiana, 1943 (Box 4, Folder 18)
- Indiana-Louisiana (Box 5)
  - Indianapolis, Indiana, 1947 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Indianapolis, Indiana, 1942-1946 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Indianapolis, Indiana, 1941-1943 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Gary and Hammond, Indiana, 1941-1945 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Indianapolis, Indiana, 1943-1949 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Gary, Indiana, 1945-1948 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Des Moines, Iowa, 1943 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Des Moines, Iowa, 1941-1943 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Wichita, Kansas, 1941-1942 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Wichita, Kansas, 1943 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Wichita, Kansas, 1943 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Louisville, Kentucky, 1942-1947 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Louisville, Kentucky, 1941-1943 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Louisville, Kentucky, 1941-1944 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Kentucky, 1941 (Box 5, Folder 15)
    The Wadsworth Watch Case Co.
  - Baton Rouge, Louisiana, 1942-1946 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - New Orleans, Louisiana, 1941-1947 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - New Orleans, Louisiana, 1941-1944 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Shreveport, Louisiana, 1944 (Box 5, Folder 19)
- Louisiana-North Carolina (Box 6)
  - Shreveport, Louisiana, 1944-1947 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Shreveport, Louisiana, 1946 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Shreveport, Louisiana, 1941-1944 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - New Orleans, Louisiana, 1941-1942 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - New Orleans, Louisiana, 1943-1948 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Baton Rouge and New Orleans, Louisiana, 1944-1949 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Baltimore, Maryland, 1942-1943 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Baltimore, Maryland, 1941 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Baltimore, Maryland, 1941-1944 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Baltimore, Maryland, 1941 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Baltimore, Maryland, 1940-1942 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Baltimore, Maryland, 1941-1944 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Baltimore, Maryland, 1944 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Baltimore, Maryland, 1944-1945 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Baltimore, Maryland, 1942-1944 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - St. Louis, Missouri, 1948 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Washington, North Carolina, 1944 (Box 6, Folder 17)
    April 15 1944